Rahul Katariya

Date of Birth: 24th January 1991

Address: 231/GH4, Meera Apartments, Paschim Vihar, New Delhi - 110063

Phone: +91 9899155309
Email: rahulkatariya@me.com
Website: http://rahulkatariya.com

Profile Summary

Rahul is a Mobile Consultant with strong skill set in iOS Development.

He has 2 years of professional experience in Web and Mobile Technologies. He has good understanding of Object Oriented Design and Design Patterns including Model View Controller (MVC), Model View ViewModel (MVVM), Target-Action, Delegate Pattern, Singleton and so on. He has a good understanding of Agile methodologies like Test Driven Development (TDD).

He has good understanding of iOS Technologies including Foundation, UIKit, CoreData, iCloud, Concurrency, Blocks, Locations and Maps, Networking, Bluetooth, Local and Remote Notifications, Static Libraries, Frameworks, Instruments, Xcode Server CI and so on.

He has also worked in Web Technologies like HTML5/CSS3, Twitter Bootstrap, LESS, SASS & Compass, Javascript, AngularJS.

He is a focused, dedicated and self-motivated person with good communication, presentation, consulting and organizational skills.

Skills and Expertise

Frontend Technologies: C, Objective-C, Swift, HTML5/CSS3, SASS, Javascript

Backend Technologies: Core Data, Parse

Frameworks:

iOS: RestKit, ReactiveCocoa, Alamofire, Parse, MBProgressHUD, Mogenerator,

CocoaLumberjack, Estimote-iOSSDK, AFNetworking and many more

Web: Twitter Bootstrap for HTML5/CSS3, AngularJS for Javascript, Compass for SASS.

Tools: Xcode, Git, JIRA, Photoshop, SketchApp

Dependency Manager:

iOS: Cocoapods, Carthage

Web: Bower, NPM

Build Tools:

iOS: Apple Server, Jenkins **Web:** Grunt, Yeoman

Employment Details

- Mobile Consultant at Xebia IT Architects Private Limited May 2014 - Present
- Associate Software Engineer at Empeiria Consulting Pvt. Ltd October 2014 - May 2014
- Technologist at Empeiria Consulting Pvt. Ltd.
 March 2013 August 2013

Experience

Projects at Xebia IT Architects Private Limited

Name	The Montcalm
Туре	iOS Application (iOS6 and iOS7)
Technologies Used	Xcode, Objective-C and UIKit, Core Data
Preview	http://preview.rahulkatariya.com/montcalm
Deliverables	Developed a mobile application for the Montcalm London Hotel to manage their client reservation system using Storyboard, Auto Layout and Core Data. Developed code to integrate with the RESTful web services.

Projects at Empeiria Consulting Private Limited

Name	ClearTM
Туре	iPad Application (iOS6 and iOS7)
Technologies Used	Xcode, Objective-C and UIKit, Core Data
Preview	http://preview.rahulkatariya.com/montcalm
Deliverables	Developed a mobile application for the Montcalm London Hotel to manage their client reservation system using Storyboard, Auto Layout and Core Data. Developed code to integrate with the RESTful web services using NSURLConnection.

Name	The Montcalm
Туре	iPhone Application (iOS6 and iOS7)
Technologies Used	Xcode, Objective-C and UIKit, Core Data
Preview	http://preview.rahulkatariya.com/montcalm

Deliverables	Developed a mobile application for the Montcalm London Hotel to manage their client reservation system using Storyboard, Auto Layout
	and Core Data. Developed code to integrate with the RESTful web services using NSURLConnection.

Name	TBN Europe
Туре	iPhone Application (iOS6 and iOS7)
Technologies Used	Xcode, Objective-C and UIKit
Preview	http://preview.rahulkatariya.com/tbneurope
Deliverables	Developed a content based application for a television network that allows mobile users to preview and watch videos. The user interface is developed on storyboard using Auto Layout. Developed code to integrate with the RESTful web services using NSURLConnection.

Name	StopAtDoc
Туре	PSD To HTML
Technologies Used	HTML5, CSS3 and jQuery
Preview	http://preview.rahulkatariya.com/stopatdoc
Deliverables	Converted PSD Screens to HTML5/CSS3 for a website that facilitates patient management for a large medical institution.

Name	IIHS
Туре	Website
Technologies Used	PHP/MySQL and Codelgniter
Preview	http://preview.rahulkatariya.com/iihs
Deliverables	Developed a student application management system to facilitate admission for an urban development institute. The web application allows users to register, apply, provide information and upload their documents through an attractive user-friendly interface. Faculty can review and track student application and Administrator can track the results.

Academic Projects

Projects as Summer Trainee at Ocean Blue Communications

Name	SilverSandsVillas
------	-------------------

Туре	Static Website
Technologies Used	HTML/CSS and jQuery
Preview	www.silver-sands-villas.com
Deliverables	Conceptualized, designed and developed the holiday content website.

Name	YourTeaMate
Туре	SEO
Preview	www.yourteamate.com
Technologies Used	Google Webmaster Tools
Deliverables	Carried out onsite SEO for a tea merchant website. Improved its site structure, optimized images, headings, content, links, page titles, keyword and description meta-tags and made use of Google Analytics.

Name	OceanBlueCommunications
Туре	Blog
Technologies Used	Wordpress
Preview	www.oceanbluecommunications.com
Deliverables	Conceptualized, designed and developed the content management system.

Education

- Bachelors in Computer Applications from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University, Delhi in 2013 with 75%.
- 12th (Commerce w/ Mathematics) From CBSE in 2009 with 75%. 10th From CBSE in 2007 with 82%.